Guide to the Pettigrew Papers
Yale University Library
- General Correspondence Files, 1797-1865; Series I:; 4.59' (13 boxes)
  - Morgan, John Minter, 1782-1854. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830-33 (Box 8, Folder 386)
    One letter introduces a Dr. Bergen, an expert in the field of education.
  - Morley, Edmund Parker, 2d Earl of, 1810-1864. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861 Apr 30 (Box 8, Folder 387)
    About Morley's participation in a congress of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Mudge, William, 1762-1820. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1816 Jan 5 (Box 9, Folder 388)
    Acknowledges his election to the Philosophical Society of London as an honorary member.
  - Müller, William, d. 1846. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1820-29 (Box 9, Folder 389)
  - Mulready, William, 1786-1863. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849 Jan 8 (Box 9, Folder 390)
    Declines to serve on a committee to establish a medal for painting and sculpture in honor of Robert Vernon.
  - Munro, Hugh Andrew Johnstone, 1819-1885. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849 Jan 17 (Box 9, Folder 391)
    Declines to participate in a testimonial for Robert Vernon.
  - Munster, George Augustus Frederick Fitzclarence, 1st Earl of, 1794-1842. 4 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1823-31 (Box 9, Folder 392)
    One letter shows that Pettigrew sought unsuccessfully the post of Librarian to the King. Also contains 1 ALS fragment.
  - Murdoch, Thomas, b. 1757. 4 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1831-34 (Box 9, Folder 393)
  - Murray, John, 1808-1892. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 394)
    Discusses the sale of one of Pettigrew's books.
  - Nares, Robert, 1753-1829. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 395)
  - Nash, John, 1752-1835. 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1828, 1829 (Box 9, Folder 396)
  - Nayler, Sir George, 1764?-1831. 2 ALS and 1 LS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827-30 (Box 9, Folder 397)
  - Needham, Francis Henry, 1819-1902. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1846 Mar 31 (Box 9, Folder 398)
    Invites Pettigrew to become a member of the London Genealogical Society.
  - Newman, John, 1786-1859. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1834 Jun 24 (Box 9, Folder 399)
    Letter accompanied payment of £100 for Pettigrew's medical services.
  - Nichols, John Bowyer, 1779-1863. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1828, 1844 (Box 9, Folder 400)
    Discusses Pettigrew's works.
  - Nichols, John Gough, 1806-1873. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 401)
    Letters discuss various details pertaining to Nichols occupation as a printer.
  - Nicolas, [John] Toup, 1788-1851. ALS to Mr. Smyth, [1849?] Jun 16 (Box 9, Folder 402)
    Discusses Lord Nelson and Lady Hamilton, presumably pertaining to Pettigrew's work.
  - Nightingale, Margaret (Goostry). ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1825 Jan 10 (Box 9, Folder 403)
    Thanks Pettigrew and others of the Literary Fund Society for their gift, following Joseph Nightingale's death.
  - Northampton, Spencer Joshua Alwyne, 2d Marquis of, 1790-1851. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1848 Mar 28 (Box 9, Folder 404)
  - Northumberland, Algernon Percy, 4th Duke of, 1792-1865. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1834-61 (Box 9, Folder 405)
    About a congress of the British Archaeological Association and some of Northumberland's opinions on the settlement of Great Britain, The Duke agrees to subscribe to several of Pettigrew's books and recommends Joseph Bonomi as an illustrator. Signs "Prudhoe" in 2 of the letters.
  - Northwick, John Rushout, 2d Baron, 1811-1887. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 406)
  - Numismatic Society. LS (signed Henry Christmas) to C. R. Smith, 1846 Feb 5 (Box 9, Folder 407)
    Announces a meeting of the Numismatic Society.
  - Oldfield, John, 1789-1863. 6 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1837-38 (Box 9, Folder 408)
    About Pettigrew's interest in mummies.
  - Ollivant, Alfred, Bp. of Llandaff, 1798-1882. 2 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1854 Jun-Sep (Box 9, Folder 409)
    Declines to subscribe to one of Pettigrew's books and to the British Archaeological Association.
  - Ord, John Walker, 1811-1853. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1835]-45 (Box 9, Folder 410)
    About the alleged mismanagement of Charing Cross Hospital, Ord's Metropolitan Literary Journal, and the Brit. Arch. Assoc.'s schism forming the Arch. Inst. Ord suggests Pettigrew publish a medical journal.
  - Ouseley, Sir Gore, 1770-1884. 2 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829-36 (Box 9, Folder 411)
    Agrees to subscribe to Pettigrew's book on mummies.
  - Outram, Sir Benjamin Fonseca, 1774-1856. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1828]-38 (Box 9, Folder 412)
  - Ouvry, Frederic, 1814-1881. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1858 Feb (Box 9, Folder 413)
    Asks Pettigrew to support his candidacy to the Athenaeum.
  - Overstone, Samuel Jones Lloyd, 1st Baron, 1796-1883. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Sep 17 (Box 9, Folder 414)
  - Papworth, Edgar George, 1809-1886. ALS (AL in different hand) to T. J. Pettigrew, 1842 Aug 22 (Box 9, Folder 415)
  - Parke, Henry, 1792?-1835. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1835 Mar 14 (Box 9, Folder 416)
    About a medal to be presented to Sir John Soane.
  - Patten, George, 1801-1865. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849 Apr (Box 9, Folder 417)
    Thanks Pettigrew for his support of his work.
  - Peacock, George, 1791-1858. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1857 Jul, Aug (Box 9, Folder 418)
    On plans for the British Archaeological Assn. to visit Ely.
  - Peel, Sir Robert, bart., 1788-1850. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 419)
  - Peile, Thomas Williamson, 1806-1882. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1853 Jan 15 (Box 9, Folder 420)
  - Penn, John, 1760-1834. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1811 May 9 (Box 9, Folder 421)
    About Sir Walter Scott who, Penn notes, "has considerable genius too much alloyed by bad taste."
  - Pennethorne, Sir James, 1801-1871. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Jan 23 (Box 9, Folder 422)
  - Pepys, William Hasledine, 1775-1856. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1832 May 3 (Box 9, Folder 423)
  - Pereira, Jonathan, 1804-1853. 2 ALS and 3 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1830]-38 (Box 9, Folder 424)
    In one letter he asks Pettigrew to support his candidacy for the Royal Society.
  - Petre, William Bernard Petre, 12th Baron, 1817-1884. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861 Apr 25 (Box 9, Folder 425)
  - Pettigrew, Thomas Joseph, 1791-1865
    - ALS to the British Archaeological Association, 1854 Nov 23 (Box 9, Folder 426)
      Petition to call an extra ordinary general meeting of the B. A. A. Signed by 2 other members.
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, 1856 Sep 4 (Box 9, Folder 427)
  - Pettigrew, William. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 428)
    About an attempt to gain the Duke of Sussex's patronage for a work purporting to be the Book of Jasher. William Pettigrew suspects it is merely a reprint (by C. R. Bond) of Jacob Ilive's fraudulent 1751 edition.
  - Philip, Alexander Philip Williamson, 1770?-1851?. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1831, 1838 (Box 9, Folder 429)
  - Phillipps, Sir Thomas, 1792-1872. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830-31 (Box 9, Folder 430)
  - Phillips, Thomas, 1770-1845. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1832]-37 (Box 9, Folder 431)
  - Phillpotts, Henry, Bp. of Exeter, 1778-1869. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1832, 1861 (Box 9, Folder 432)
    About the condition of Hudson Gurney.
  - Phipps, Sir Charles Beaumont, 1801-1866. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849, 1855 (Box 9, Folder 433)
    Announces donations from the Queen and Prince Albert for the Robert Vernon Testimonial and the British Archaeological Association.
  - Pickersgill, Henry William, 1782-1875. 5 ALS and 3 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1832-49 (Box 9, Folder 434)
    Some of the letters discuss the Robert Vernon testimonial.
  - Pidgeon, Henry Clark, 1807-1880. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849, 1850 (Box 9, Folder 435)
    About arrangements between the British Archaeological Association and the Historic Society of Lancashire and Cheshire.
  - Pitcairn, Robert, 1793-1855. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1823 or later] (Box 9, Folder 436)
  - Pitts, William, 1790-1840. 2 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1831 May (Box 9, Folder 437)
    On several of Pitt's works.
  - Planché, James Robinson, 1796-1880. 11 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830-58 (Box 9, Folder 438)
    In one letter he discusses the publication of the British Archaeological Association's Journal by Henry Bohn.
  - Poltimore, Augustus Frederick George Warwick Bampfylde, 2d Baron, 1837-1908. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1860 or later] (Box 9, Folder 439)
  - Pomfret, George Fermor, 3d Earl of, 1768-1830. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1827 or later] (Box 9, Folder 440)
  - Pond, John, 1767-1836. 6 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1831 Feb-Jul (Box 9, Folder 441)
    On the Royal Society.
  - Poste, Beale, 1793-1871. 8 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1847-52 (Box 9, Folder 442)
    On several of Poste's major books and articles for the Journal of the British Archaeological Assn., especially on numismatics.
  - Powis, Edward James Herbert, 3d Earl of, 1818-1891. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1860 Jul, Oct (Box 9, Folder 443)
    Agrees to a visit by the British Archaeological Association.
  - Poynder, John, 1779-1849. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1847 Jul-Aug (Box 9, Folder 444)
    On the death of Pettigrew's wife and antiquarian matters pertaining to Pettigrew's studies on mummies.
  - Prout, William, 1783-1852. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1838 Feb 24 (Box 9, Folder 445)
  - Purland, Theophilius. ALS to Thomas Wright, 1846 Feb 2 (Box 9, Folder 446)
    Proposes Cozette Ladent for membership in the British Archaeological Association.
  - Radnor, Jacob Pleydell-Bouverie, 8th Earl of, 1815-1889. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1858 Jun 16 (Box 10, Folder 447)
    Concerns a visit of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Reeve, Lovell Augustus, 1814-1865. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1852-53 (Box 10, Folder 448)
    About the attention paid to the British Archaeological Association by Reeve's Literary Gazette. Reeve asks Pettigrew to support his candidacy for the Royal Society.
  - Rennie, Sir John, 1794-1874. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1834 or later] (Box 10, Folder 449)
  - Renouard, George Cecil, 1780-1867. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1824, 1836 (Box 10, Folder 450)
    About Pettigrew's work with mummies.
  - Richards, George, 1767-1837. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829 Feb 2 (Box 10, Folder 451)
    Compliments Pettigrew's practice and recommends him for post of medical superintendent of the poor in the workhouse of St. James.
  - Richardson, Charles James, 1806-1871. ALS to James R. Planché, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 452)
    Letter indicates that Richardson was F. S. A. and Fellow of the Institute of British Architects.
  - Richardson, Moses Aaron, 1793-1871. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1847 Nov 26 (Box 10, Folder 453)
    Letter show Richardson's intent to write a history of Newcastle and Gateshead.
  - Riego, Miguel del. 8 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew and 1 ALS to the Duke of Sussex, [1823-28] (Box 10, Folder 454)
    In one letter he introduces Patrick MacDowell to Pettigrew and solicits Pettigrew's assistance for gaining recognition of his work.
  - Rifaud, J. J. 1 AL to T.J. Pettigrew and Prospectus, signed, for Voyage en Égypte, et en Nubie, 1827. (Box 10, Folder 455)
    See Moreau, César, for identical prospectus.
  - Rigby, Edward, 1804-1860. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 456)
    Due to his financial condition Rigby declines to subscribe to Pettigrew's book on mummies.
  - Rimbault, Edward Francis, 1816-1876. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1841 Apr-May (Box 10, Folder 457)
    Pettigrew's election to the Council of the Percy Society.
  - Roberts, David, 1796-1864. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1846-51 (Box 10, Folder 458)
    Discusses an archaeological project involving Sir John Wilkinson in one letter.
  - Roberts, P[eter?], 1760?-1819. ALS to unidentified., 1797 Jul 25 (Box 10, Folder 459)
    Discusses Indian antiquities.
  - Robertson, Andrew, 1777-1845. 1 ALS and 3 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829-32 (Box 10, Folder 460)
  - Robinson, Peter Frederick, 1776-1858. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 461)
  - Roe, George Hamilton, 1795-1873. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 462)
  - Rogers, William Harry, 1825-1873. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1847-50 (Box 10, Folder 463)
  - Roget, Peter Mark, 1779-1869. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827-40 (Box 10, Folder 464)
    Congratulates Pettigrew on his election to the Royal Society and provides information for Pettigrew's Medical Portrait Gallery.
  - Rokewode, John Gage, 1786-1842. 7 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1826-40 (Box 10, Folder 465)
    Agrees to subscribe to one of Pettigrew's books and indicates support for the candidacy of the Duke of Sussex for the presidency of the Royal Society.
  - Room, Henry, 1802-1850. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 466)
  - Rowan, Sir Charles, 1782-1852. ALS and LS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830, 1833 (Box 10, Folder 467)
    On two recommendations from Pettigrew for prospective employment on the police force.
  - Royal Botanic Society. LS (signed James Sowerby) to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849 Jun 11 (Box 10, Folder 468)
  - Royal Society of London. LS (signed Davies Gilbert) to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829 Nov 16 (Box 10, Folder 469)
  - Rudge, Edward, 1763-1846. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1833 (Box 10, Folder 470)
  - Sabine, Sir Edward, 1788-1883. LS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1828 Feb 11 (Box 10, Folder 471)
    Thanks Pettigrew on behalf of the Royal Society for a copy of the Bibliotheca Sussexiana.
  - Sabine, Joseph, 1770-1837. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1820, 1834 (Box 10, Folder 472)
    Letters mention the Horticultural Society.
  - Sala, Henrietta Catherina Florentina (Simon), 1789-1860. 1 ALS to T.J. Pettigrew, [1828] (Box 10, Folder 473)
    Letter announces death of Augustus John James Sala (1792-1828).
  - Salisbury, William. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1832 Jun 10 (Box 10, Folder 474)
    On a series of lectures to be given by Salisbury. Included is a printed syllabus for those lectures.
  - Sass, Henry, 1788-1844. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1826]-31 (Box 10, Folder 475)
    One of the letters introduces "Mr. Martin the distinguished artist."
  - Saull, William Devonshire, 1784-1855. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1852 Aug 9 (Box 10, Folder 476)
    On a paper Saull wrote on Roman roads in England.
  - Saumarez, Richard, 1764-1835. 1 ALS to T.J. Pettigrew, [1815 or later] (Box 10, Folder 477)
  - Sayer, Augustin, 1790-1861. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1828], 1833 (Box 10, Folder 478)
  - Scott, John. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1832]-53 (Box 10, Folder 479)
    Introduces Matthew Noble in one letter; another mentions a play by James Knowles, Barristers.
  - Scudamore, Sir Charles, 1779-1849. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1841 or later] (Box 10, Folder 480)
    Queries why he was omitted from Pettigrew's Medical Portrait Gallery.
  - Scudamore, Georgiana (Johnson), lady. 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1849] (Box 10, Folder 481)
    One letter mentions the death of Sir Charles Scudamore.
  - Sedgwick, Adam, 1785-1873. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1840-[46] (Box 10, Folder 482)
  - Seymour, Edward James, 1796-1866. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 483)
  - Shakespear, John, 1774-1858. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1833 Jul 3 (Box 10, Folder 484)
  - Sharp, Sir Cuthbert, 1781-1849. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845 Mar 28 (Box 10, Folder 485)
    Offers some suggestions for the recently formed British Archaeological Association.
  - Sharp, William, 1805-1896. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1839 Nov 13 (Box 10, Folder 486)
    Agrees to subscribe to Pettigrew's Medical Portrait Gallery and replies to Pettigrew's request for information on Samuel Sharp.
  - Sharpe, Edmund, 1809-1877. 4 ALS and a fragment to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Jul-Sep (Box 10, Folder 487)
    On plans for the British Archaeological Association congress at Lancaster and several of Sharp's books.
  - Shaw, Alexander, 1804-1890. 2 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1839 Feb (Box 10, Folder 488)
    Letter shows the close ties between Shaw and his brother-in-law Sir Charles Bell.
  - Shee, Sir Martin Archer, 1769-1850. 3 ALS and 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1825]-31 (Box 10, Folder 489)
  - Sievier, Robert William, 1794-1865. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1816, 1825 (Box 10, Folder 490)
  - Skelton, Joseph, fl. 1820-1850. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845 Jun 18 (Box 10, Folder 491)
    Letter concerns Pettigrew's interest in one of Skelton's books.
  - Sleath, John, 1767-1847. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1828-31 (Box 10, Folder 492)
    On invitations to the Duke of Sussex for St. Paul's Apposition or "Speech Day."
  - Smart, Benjamin Humphrey 1786?-1872. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1828]-50 (Box 10, Folder 493)
    In one letter he asks Pettigrew's help to be elected to the Athenaeum.
  - Smart, Sir George Thomas, 1776-1867. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1825-47 (Box 10, Folder 494)
  - Smith, Charles John, 1803-1838. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1831 Jan 15 (Box 10, Folder 495)
    Asks Pettigrew to subscribe to one of his books.
  - Smith, Charles Roach, 1807-1890. 6 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1844-45 (Box 10, Folder 496)
    About the British Archaeological Association and its competition from the Archaeological Institute. One letter describes a trip in Germany.
  - Smith, Sir William Sidney, 1764-1840. 4 ALS to T.J. Pettigrew and 1 ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 1830-37 (Box 10, Folder 497)
    Letters introduce various friends of Smith to Pettigrew, including Antoine Clot and a M. (Marc Antoine?) Julien.
  - Smyth, William Henry, 1788-1865. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 14 ALS to unidentified., 1844-52 (Box 10, Folder 498)
    Letters discuss much of the rivalry within the Society of Antiquaries as well as with the British Archaeological Association and the Archaeological Institute. Many of the unidentified letters are addressed to "Commandante" or "General."
  - Soames, Henry, 1785-1860. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1842 Apr, May (Box 11, Folder 499)
  - Soard, J.
    - ALS (in French) to M. Moreau, 1819 May 20 (Box 11, Folder 500)
      About Soard's membership in the London Medical Society. Soard was president of La Société Académique de Médicine de Marseille.
    - ALS (in French) to T. J. Pettigrew, 1819 Jul 21 (Box 11, Folder 501)
  - Société des Antiquaries de Picardie. 3 ALS (signed J. Garnie) to President of the B.A.A. and 1 ALS to President of the British Assoc. of Conservation of Monuments, 1850-51 (Box 11, Folder 502)
    Donates several works to the British Archaeological Association.
  - Solly, Edward, 1819-1866. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew and 1 ALS to Charles Roach Smith, 1845-51 (Box 11, Folder 503)
    Letter indicate that although a member, Solly did not play an active part in the British Archaeological Association.
  - Somerset, Edward Adolphus Seymour, 11th Duke of, 1775-1855. 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830, 1833 (Box 11, Folder 504)
    In one letter, the Duke indicates his disgust for the Royal Society.
  - Southey, Henry Herbert, 1783-1865. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 505)
  - Spence, William, 1783-1858. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1847, 1848 (Box 11, Folder 506)
  - Spencer, John Charles Spencer, 3d Earl, 1782-1845. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1822 Feb 27 (Box 11, Folder 507)
  - Spring-Rice, William Cecil, 1823-1880. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Apr (Box 11, Folder 508)
  - Spurgin, John, 1797-1866. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1829]-45 (Box 11, Folder 509)
  - Squier, Ephraim George, 1821-1888. 3 ALS to T.J. Pettigrew and 1 ALS to Charles Roach Smith, 1849-52 (Box 11, Folder 510)
    On Squier's election to the British Archaeological Association and several of his works.
  - Stanfield, Clarkson, 1793-1867. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1846 Jun 3 (Box 11, Folder 511)
    Accepts his election to the British Archaeological Association, although he expects to be of little value to it.
  - Stanley, Edward John Stanley, 2d Baron, 1802-1869. 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1857 Jul, Oct (Box 11, Folder 512)
    Accepts the position of vice president of the British Archaeological Association, but declines to subscribe or attend.
  - Stapleton, Thomas, 1805-1849. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1839]-45 (Box 11, Folder 513)
    Letters mention some meetings of the Society of Antiquaries.
  - Streatfield, Thomas, 1777-1848. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1844 Sep 8 (Box 11, Folder 514)
    On antiquarian subjects relating to the British Archaeological Assn.
  - Strutt, Jacob George, fl. 1820-1850. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 1823 Apr 21 (Box 11, Folder 515)
    Seeks the support of the Duke of Sussex for his "Sylva Britannica."
  - Stuart de Decies, Henry Villiers Stuart, 1st Baron, 1803-1874. AL to Mr. Stephenson, [1828 or later] (Box 11, Folder 516)
  - Suckling, Alfred Inigo, 1796-1856. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845 Mar 17 (Box 11, Folder 517)
    Declines to become a member of the Archaeological Society. Letter is written on sheet which contains a printed prospectus of his Memorials.
  - Sykes, William Henry, 1790-1872. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1839-52 (Box 11, Folder 518)
  - Symmons, Charles, 1749-1826. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1824 Jun 9 (Box 11, Folder 519)
  - Talman, J. J. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1817 Jan 16 (Box 11, Folder 520)
    Discusses land speculation in England and Pettigrew's unsuccessful venture.
  - Tankerville, Charles Bennet, 6th Earl of, 1810-1899. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1832]-33 (Box 11, Folder 521)
    Agrees to subscribe to one of Pettigrew's works. Signs "Ossulston."
  - Taylor, Edward, 1784-1863. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1824-31 (Box 11, Folder 522)
    Letters discuss several of Taylor's books, including Spohr's "Last Judgement." One letter is about Benjamin Fawcett's and John Taylor's volume of sermons, presumably collected by Edward Taylor.
  - Taylor, Sir Herbert, 1775-1839. 1 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 3 ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 1 ALS to Col. Fitzclarence., 1815-33 (Box 11, Folder 523)
    On Pettigrew's attempts to obtain military positions for friends and his son. One letter grants permission for Pettigrew to inscribe his book on mummies to the King.
  - Taylor, John, 1757-1832. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, with three poems, 1826-31 (Box 11, Folder 524)
    Letters discuss Sir Robert Porter and Lawrence MacDonald. Poems commemorate Charles Symmons's death and the Duke of Sussex's election to the presidency of the Royal Society.
  - Taylor, Michael Angelo, 1757-1834. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827 Nov 21 (Box 11, Folder 525)
  - Taylor, Thomas, 1758-1835. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1834 Feb-May (Box 11, Folder 526)
    Letters discuss a legal action involving Taylor. Mentions Isaac Preston Cory as a barrister. Includes a two page extract of Marsilio Ficino's De Vita (in Latin) and Sir Francis Bacon's Natural History.
  - Thelwall, [John?], 1764-1834. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1826 Mar 15 (Box 11, Folder 527)
    Seeks support from the Duke of Sussex for a magazine, possibly The Champion.
  - Thomas, Honoratus Leigh, 1769-1846. 6 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1823]-38 (Box 11, Folder 528)
    Agrees to subscribe to several of Pettigrew's books. One letter discusses the recognition of Charing Cross Hospital "as a school of surgery."
  - Thompson, James, 1817-1877. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Nov 30 (Box 11, Folder 529)
  - Thoms, William John, 1803-1885. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1844 Feb (Box 11, Folder 530)
    In one letter Thoms accepts on behalf of the Camden Society Pettigrew's offer to edit three 12th-14th century medical tracts.
  - Thomson, Anthony Todd, 1778-1849. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1836, 1840 (Box 11, Folder 531)
    On medical appointments and Pettigrew's Medical Portrait Gallery, which apparently was not a success.
  - Thomson, William, ABp. of York, 1819-1890. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1863-65 (Box 11, Folder 532)
    On the British Archaeological Assn.
  - Tite, Sir William, 1798-1873. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1840 Oct 6 (Box 11, Folder 533)
  - Tod, James, 1782-1835. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [n.d.] (Box 11, Folder 534)